KURT STATHAM

SUMMARY

A 12-year veteran of the casual game industry in search of my next challenge. Extensive QA and site production experience. Adept at multitasking with a keen desire to apply new skills and concepts. Strong communication, collaboration, problem-solving and analytical skills. Experienced in building and maintaining websites from conception to production.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Python, MySQL, MongoDB, Java, HTML, CSS, Shell Scripting

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES: React, Node.js, Express, jQuery, NPM, Bootstrap, Materialize

OTHER TECH: Git, SVN, Jira, Mac, Linux, Windows, Command Line

EMPLOYMENT

DEFY Media, Director, Site Production, Los Angeles, CA

Apr. 2017 - Oct. 2018

- Managed all scheduling and production for the Addicting Games and Shockwave websites.
- Reviewed and approved all prospective Shockwave site content.
- Served as the technical liaison between the site production and engineering teams.
- Successfully built and maintained relationships with a variety of content providers.
- Identified and remedied any production-related site issues improving customer experience.
- Trained and mentored junior staff.

Nickelodeon/DEFY Media, Game Release Engineer, Los Angeles, CA

July 2011 - Mar. 2017

- Produced and tested games for the Addicting Games and Shockwave websites.
- Maintained and improved legacy production systems.
- Wrote scripts to automate and streamline game production.
- Coordinated content delivery for dozens of daily titles ensuring minimal service disruption.

Nickelodeon, Games Tester, San Francisco, CA

June 2008 - June 2011

- Identified and isolated game and site issues.
- Verification of bug fixes/regression testing.
- Ensured a consistent user experience across all titles.

Nickelodeon, Assistant Manager, Customer Support, San Francisco, CA

Apr. 2007 - May 2008

- Assisted customers with technical issues and billing inquiries.
- Supervised and trained junior staff.
- Organized and oversaw team projects.

EDUCATION

UCLA Extension

Certificate Full Stack Web Development 2019

City College of San Francisco

Certificate Java Programming 2010

University of California, Berkeley

B.A. French 2003